Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
As soon as Golem is damaged, it begins to sing…
…the song of destruction which will kill manmade cells…
…that echoes through the universe.
Gatlantis fleet formation has been broken. Their communications have gone silent.
They're completely out of control.
So finally…
All ships, leave the battlefield !
As I thought.
The Gatlantian who has eaten the seed of wisdom,
is not allowed to go with the rest, I suppose.
Kodai, do you hear me ?
The assault team should
withdraw as soon as possible.
This is not just the effect from Golem.
Something unknown is destroying the imperial capital,
and absorbing everything around it, including the energy.
Oh no...
...the Ark of Destruction is spontaneously
consuming the imperial capital…
Lieutenant Keyman, get back to the ship.
At this rate, the Yamato…
First Officer Sanada...
...I have an idea.
To destroy an evil species, and
fulfill the duty given by the creator…
…the Ark of Destruction always
evolves to take the optimal shape.
Whether it houses dwellers like
Gatlantis or not, is not important.
It only needs a judge who
prompts the destruction…
…based on the will of a human.
Wait !
I am a human !
I demand the true awakening
of the Ark of Destruction !
Kodai, are you alright ?
Wait...
Don't do it, Zorder !
Zorder, don't !
Kodai, we're leaving !
Zorder !
Assault team, withdraw at will !
The Yamato has sustained
serious damage to the engine...
...and its internal pressure is reaching critical !
I've never done this before.
I don't know how long it'll last.
Mr. Tokugawa…Yamato…
Everything is getting sucked into the
opening of the gravitational core !
The energy signature of the imperial
capital is getting even stronger !
That's the Ark of Destruction…
Kodai…
Mr. Sanada…?!
The only way to stop this monster is...
...to destroy its energy converter from the
inside before it finishes the energy conversion.
That's the only way.
From inside…
Keyman !
This must be fate.
My ship's loaded with the last of the
wave motion excavator warheads.
That thing is absorbing everything to
satisfy a thousand years of hunger.
Now is the chance…
Wait, Keyman !
That's not your call !
I'll do it !
Turn around, Keyman !
I beg you. I don't want
to lose anyone anymore !
Your travel buddy's here, Gammy !
All fighter unit pilots, please...
...escort Captain Kodai back to the Yamato.
He has so much left to…
This is too sad !
As always, you live for someone else...
...instead of living...
...the life that's best for you…
Not really.
It's even more sad if you only
live for your own benefit, right ?
Everyone lives, searching
for something precious.
If you think you're going to
lose it, you'd risk your life.
What else can I do,
now that I've found it ?
Same here.
Kodai, please let them go.
Treat him like a human until the end.
Kodai ! You'd better
listen to my wifey…
…or you'll get your ass kicked.
Saito…
Please, for our sake…
Grab the future with your hands.
Gammy, hurry, but be calm and precise !
Akira, I never thought
I was sad because…
...I didn't have anyone who
made me sad of losing.
But now, I'm sad that
I can't hear your voice…
…sad that I can't see your face.
I guess it can't be helped.
The more you gain and feel happy,
the greater the sadness becomes.
Commander, thank you.
I'll embrace the sadness.
Yamamoto !
Saito, Keyman…
Is...is that…?
As I said, you can't stop it.
You and humanity
lost your future long ago.
Accept your salvation.
It's the only salvation that
can end your suffering.
Die.
This is farewell to the warriors of Earth,
the ones who won't pull the trigger.
Gatlantis is heading to Saturn's coordinates.
It's going to convert the remaining
core of Saturn to attack Earth…
We have no means left to stop it.
All hands...
...abandon ship.
Earth might lose its planetary
function with the next attack.
But, even so…
...every one of us must live
for as long as possible.
Even if such a choice
is harder than dying.
Humanity must live on.
Kodai…!
Kodai stayed behind !
As long as we have a chance…
I've heard of Plan G.
I want you to leave the Solar System as
soon as possible to look for a new Earth.
Wait !
Captain Kodai, you are…!
Mr. Okita…
…I'll hear your recrimination once I join you.
Yuki, why ?
You disobeyed the evacuation order…
I'll navigate.
Crash the Yamato into it, right ?
Even the near-critical wave motion engine
won't be able to destroy a mass that large.
But you can get time to evacuate as many people
as possible from Earth before the core recharges…
Yuki…
I…
…don't remember you...
...but I know that's what's on your mind.
Yuki…
Kodai…
...you can't do this alone.
The Yamato's going.
We can't waste this chance.
Speed up the evacuation plan.
A thousand years ago,
you reactivated the Ark of Destruction.
Do you know why you were able to do it ?
Because you're human.
Because you are human, you hate
people and try to annihilate them.
Because you are human, you
love and try to protect humans.
Wave motion engine,
internal pressure 250%.
The reactor is near critical, but we
can still reach the Ark of Destruction.
So warm.
Yuki…
Kodai…
That light…
Teresa…
Memories are mere sediment.
Love gives birth to humans, and builds fate.
Everything follows its fate.
And my fate with you
has brought me here.
The out-of-control wave motion engine opened
a hole to a higher dimension, and brought Teresa.
Is it a one-in-a-million coincidence...
...or inevitability ?
The Yamato is a vessel that can
bring Teresa to our universe.
A strong will can change
the pre-determined future.
Another strong will was
necessary to change the course.
One missing person, and
I wouldn't be able to come here.
I also am a part of the great harmony.
Let's go together for the sake of all
living things which build the future.
Episode 25
Farewell, Space Battleship Yamato
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Saijo Miki :
Kato Saburo:
Kato Makoto:
Kato Tsubasa:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Yamamoto Akira:
Sawamura Sho:
Takuma Takeshi:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Kenich Suzumura
Otsuka Hochu
Mugihito
Akabane Kenji
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Sato Rina
Takamori Natsumi
Hirakawa Daisuke
Tanaka Rie
Shikaki  Yuya
Kijima Koichi
Tsuchida Hiroshi
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Kurata Masaru:
Todo Saki:
Hijikata Ryu:
Yamanami Osamu:
Todo Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu
Operator:
Tochi Hiroyuki
Amagai Kazusa
Kiyohito Yoshikai
Takagaki Ayahi
Kusumi Naomi
Ebara Masashi
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Fujinuma Kento
Cottony clouds drift high across the sky
Sora takaku nagareru kieyuku wata no kumo
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Loren Barrel:
Gadel Talan:
Zorder:
Mill:
Yamadera Koichi
Kamiya Hiroshi
Terasoma Masaki
Nakamura Kotaro
Tezuka Hideaki
Uchiyama Koki
Holding out both hands, I stretch out in the falling leaves
Ryoote wo age ah senobi shita rakuyou
As the house lights come on, I wish to meet people smiling at each other
Akari tomoru mado waraiau hito ni aitai to omou
Believing in a miraculous enounter to become real, I shout out for love
Sou kanau hazusa kiseki no deai ni ai sakenda
Luminous lives meet and bond with each other
Kagayaku jinsei no meguriawase tsumuideyuku
Let’s keep on living our lives
Bokura no jinsei wo tayumazu ni susumi tsuzukeyou
Let’s begin the story of our lives
Bokura no jinsei no monogatari wo saa hajimeyou
Preview
I pulled the trigger.
Kodai !
What a mess…
We might be being tested.
We've got things to do.
Everything's determined by your desire.
You can have your ideal world if you so wish.
Final Episode
Earth, the Yamato is…